<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
  xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
  xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
  xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

  <channel>
    <title>Buckingham Strategic Partners</title>
    <atom:link href="https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/feed/?cat=-600%2C-98" rel="self"
      type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/</link>
    <description></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 18:15:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
      hourly </sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
      1 </sy:updateFrequency>


    <image>
      <url>
        https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/BSP_Logo_Color_Icon-Only.png</url>
      <title>Buckingham Strategic Partners</title>
      <link>https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">223786052</site>
    <item>
      <title>The Value of a Financial Advisor: How to Consider the Costs and Benefits</title>
      <link>
        https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/perspectives/the-value-of-a-financial-advisor-how-to-consider-the-costs-and-benefits/</link>

      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Buckingham Strategic Partners]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 09:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">
        https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/perspectives/the-value-of-a-financial-advisor-how-to-consider-the-costs-and-benefits/</guid>

      <description><![CDATA[In a world of do-it-yourself home improvement programs and YouTube repair videos, it can be tempting to manage your own money. So, why might one consider working with a professional? And how should you think about the costs and benefits when selecting a professional to work with? Here’s what individual investors should know when assessing...]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a world of do-it-yourself home improvement programs and YouTube repair videos, it can be tempting to manage your own money. So, why might one consider working with a professional? And how should you think about the costs and benefits when selecting a professional to work with? Here’s what individual investors should know when assessing the value of working with a financial advisor.</p>
<h2><strong>Why Partner with a Financial Advisor?</strong></h2>
<p>A financial planner can create a comprehensive, tax-efficient wealth strategy based on your goals, risk tolerance and current financial situation. Knowing you have a trusted professional helping to navigate your needs and make informed decisions also brings peace of mind.</p>
<p>While there are many ways to weigh the benefits of working with an advisor, one way is to explore the main costs you might face in your financial planning journey.</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26930 aligncenter" src="https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TheThreeCosts-300x137.png" alt="" width="823" height="376" srcset="https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TheThreeCosts-300x137.png 300w , https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TheThreeCosts-1024x466.png 1024w , https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TheThreeCosts-1536x699.png 1536w " sizes="(max-width: 823px) 100vw, 823px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Economic costs:</strong> There is an opportunity cost for choosing one investment over another. How do you know which one is right for you, for your plan and for your family? Which one will give you the greatest likelihood of achieving your financial goals?</li>
<li><strong>Tax cost:</strong> Depending on which investments you choose, there are tax costs based on the titling of the asset, the investment type, the account type and the time when you buy and sell. How do you measure the time spent navigating the different tax treatments and consequences for your investments?</li>
<li><strong>Emotional cost: </strong>What are the trade-offs between managing your priorities, and are there strategies to reduce emotional costs? What is that worth and how do you begin to quantify it?</li>
</ul>
<p>Along your journey, an advisor can help you assess these decisions and build a financial plan that aims to address your biggest needs, as well as uncovering those you may not have considered before.</p>
<h2><strong>An Advisor’s Advice Should Be Unique to You</strong></h2>
<p>Participating in an exploratory meeting specific to your needs, wants and wishes is the best way to identify if a relationship with an advisor may be beneficial and if there is value. It’s important to get a sense of the advisor’s standard of care, level of detail in their planning, how much they value building a relationship, and how they will coach you on financial behavioral decisions. When valuing an advisor, it’s best not to compare our experience with those of others. Although the relationships our parents or friends have with their advisors can shape our impression and outlook on the industry, what may be important to them and what drives their decisions may not be the same for us. Make sure your advisor is building a plan designed specifically for your needs and goals.</p>
<h2><strong>Assessing the Value for the Advisor’s Services</strong></h2>
<p>As we think about how to measure the value of an advisor, it is important to understand the evolution of the financial advice industry. The industry started as a way for wealthy individuals to gain access to financial markets. In fact, in the early 1970s, <a href="https://fraser.stlouisfed.org/files/docs/publications/SCB/pages/1970-1974/12355_1970-1974.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the top 1% of earners in the U.S. held over 50% of all outstanding stock</a>. At that time, individuals looking to make an investment in a listed security, such as a stock or bond, could only do so through stockbrokers who would earn a commission for executing the buying and selling of a listed security. Thus, individuals were optimistically paying for high investment performance as brokers would buy securities in the hope of appreciation that would also serve their own needs via commissions. Very rarely would an individual buy a security solely because of how it fits into their larger plan. This is how the financial advice industry has evolved today, as the fee-based industry began taking off.</p>
<h2><strong>The Transition to a Fee-Based Industry</strong></h2>
<p>The rise of the internet in the early 2000s paved the way for disruptors to enter the financial services market, giving the public greater access to information on pricing and investments. This drove down what were once tremendously high trading fees. Discount brokers such as online trading platforms emerged, making it easier for investors with less money to make trades. Today, with discount brokerage firms offering broader access to financial markets, trading fees are zero in some cases.</p>
<p>However, these services do not offer the investment selection guidance that stockbrokers offered. That’s where the present-day, fee-based advisor enters the picture. Although there are several models for paying for financial advice, charging a fee based on assets under management has become one of the most common.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26942 aligncenter" src="https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Evolution_Business-300x157.png" alt="graphic with blue and white text" width="955" height="500" srcset="https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Evolution_Business-300x157.png 300w , https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Evolution_Business-1024x537.png 1024w , https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Evolution_Business-768x403.png 768w , https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Evolution_Business-1536x805.png 1536w , https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Evolution_Business.png 1600w " sizes="(max-width: 955px) 100vw, 955px" /></h2>
<h2><strong>The Future of Paying for Financial Advice</strong></h2>
<p>We believe that paying a retainer to ensure you are on the right trajectory and for access to knowledge and advice that is specific to you and your circumstances is the future of the financial advice industry. It is not just paying for the answer to a specific problem but paying for the advice for unknown problems that only come through working with an objective, third-party advisor that has the professional competency, stays current, pays attention and creates the confidence that working with them will create the future you want.</p>
<p><em>For informational and educational purposes only and should not be construed as specific investment, accounting, legal, or tax advice. Certain information is based on third party data and may become outdated or otherwise superseded without notice. Third party information is deemed to be reliable, but its accurcy and completeness cannot be guaranteed. By clicking on any of the links above, you acknowledge that they are solely for your convenience, and do not necessarily imply any affiliations, sponsorships, endorsements or representations whatsoever by us regarding third-party websites. Buckingham is not responsible for the content, availability or privacy policies of these sites, and shall not be responsible or liable for any information, opinions, advice, products or services available on or through them. Neither the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) nor any other federal or state agency have approved, determined the accuracy, or confirmed the adequacy of this article.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>


      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">26928</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Economic Outlook for Q2 2024</title>
      <link>https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/perspectives/the-economic-outlook-for-q2-2024/</link>

      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Grogan, CFA, CFP®]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 14:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
        https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/perspectives/the-economic-outlook-for-q2-2024/</guid>

      <description><![CDATA[Our latest Quarterly Outlook report covered the strong and consistent growth of the U.S. economy in 2023, which grew at an annualized pace of 2.5%. So far in 2024, the U.S. has continued to be an outlier compared with other economies, growing at an estimated 2.8% annualized pace in the first quarter, while other developed...]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our latest Quarterly Outlook report covered the strong and consistent growth of the U.S. economy in 2023, which grew at an annualized pace of 2.5%. So far in 2024, the U.S. has continued to be an outlier compared with other economies, growing at an estimated 2.8% annualized pace in the first quarter, while other developed markets have experienced flat growth or are in a recession. Meanwhile, inflation is still well above the Federal Reserve’s long-run target of 2% – with core CPI rising 3.8% in the 12 months through March, the same pace as February.</p>
<p>Click <a href="https://www.buckinghamstrategicwealth.com/resources/investing/quarterly-outlook-economic-momentum-continues#entry:68007@3:url" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a> to view the full Quarterly Outlook for Q2 2024.</p>
<p>If you have any questions please feel free to drop us a <a href="https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/contact/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">note</a>.</p>
<p><em><span dir="ltr" data-redactor-span="true">For informational and educational purposes only and should not be construed as specific investment, accounting, legal, or tax advice. Certain information is based on third party data and may become outdated or otherwise superseded without notice. Third party information is deemed to be reliable, but its accuracy and completeness cannot be guaranteed. The time frame chosen because of the dates of available data. The inception of the AIEQ ETF was 2017. Indices are not available for direct investment. Their performance does not reflect the expenses associated with the management of an actual portfolio nor do indices represent results of actual trading. Information from sources deemed reliable, but its accuracy cannot be guaranteed. Performance is historical and does not guarantee future results. All investments involve risk, including loss of principal. Neither the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) nor any other federal or state agency have approved, determined the accuracy, or confirmed the adequacy of this information.</span></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>


      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">26947</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quarterly Outlook: Economic Momentum Continues</title>
      <link>
        https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/perspectives/quarterly-outlook-economic-momentum-continues/</link>

      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Buckingham Strategic Partners]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 14:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/?p=26922</guid>

      <description><![CDATA[Main Takeaway Although markets had a strong ﬁrst quarter, inﬂation has been stickier in some key areas of the economy. The services industry continues to be resilient, with employment rising and inﬂationary pressures increasing, while more interest rate sensitive areas, such as manufacturing, are weaker. The optimistic tone from the Fed has improved the outlook...]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><strong>Main Takeaway</strong></h3>
<p>Although markets had a strong ﬁrst quarter, inﬂation has been stickier in some key areas of the economy. The services industry continues to be resilient, with employment rising and inﬂationary pressures increasing, while more interest rate sensitive areas, such as manufacturing, are weaker. The optimistic tone from the Fed has improved the outlook for interest rate cuts, though less liquidity in the banking industry, plus continued ﬁscal deﬁcits, may keep rates higher for longer.</p>
<h3><strong>Top Risks</strong></h3>
<p>Rising geopolitical tensions and rate cut predictions have been the main themes this presidential election year. Low office occupancy rates have renewed concerns about the banking sector’s stability, contributing to tighter lending conditions. Municipal ﬁnances are coming under pressure in large cities. Government debt levels in most developed nations and China are at all-time highs. Inﬂationary pressures in the services sector could keep inﬂation above the Fed’s 2% target for some time.</p>
<h3><strong>Sources of Stability</strong></h3>
<p>While the Fed’s battle against inﬂation may not be over, it has made some progress in interest rate sensitive areas of the economy. House prices have stabilized and show signs of rebounding, and businesses are still increasing wages, suggesting a strong economic undercurrent. The S&amp;P 500 has continued its upward climb, credit spreads have tightened, and IPO and M&amp;A activity has picked up. The likelihood of a recession has fallen, barring an unexpected event.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<figure class="image-left" style="margin: 0px 0px 1em; padding: 0px; border: 0px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 400; font-size: 14px; line-height: inherit; font-family: 'system-ui';"><a href="https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BSP_QuarterlyOutlook_2024_Q2_0409.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" class="alignnone" src="https://buckingham-wealth.transforms.svdcdn.com/production/images/people/Q2-Quarterly-Outlook-PDF-Download-Image_4.png?w=266&amp;h=216&amp;auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;fit=crop&amp;dm=1681242362&amp;s=0b151179b2448629d459a039abda555b#asset:57465:url" alt="Quarterly Outlook PDF Download" width="266" height="216" data-image="m5gjltv2m37k" /></a></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>For our latest perspectives on markets and economic conditions, view our </strong><strong><a href="https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BSP_QuarterlyOutlook_2024_Q2_0409.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Quarterly Outlook for Q2 2024</a></strong><strong>.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>For informational and educational purposes only and should not be construed as specific investment, accounting, legal or tax advice. Certain information is based upon third party data, which may become outdated or otherwise superseded without notice. Third-party information is deemed to be reliable, but its accuracy and completeness cannot be guaranteed. Indices are not available for direct investment. Their performance does not reflect the expenses associated with the management of an actual portfolio nor do indices represent results of actual trading. Information from sources deemed reliable, but its accuracy cannot be guaranteed. Performance is historical and does not guarantee future results. Neither the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) nor any other federal or state agency have approved, determined the accuracy, or confirmed the adequacy of this article. </em></p>
<p><em>© 2024 Buckingham Wealth Partners. Buckingham Strategic Wealth, LLC, &amp; Buckingham Strategic Partners, LLC (Collectively, Buckingham Wealth Partners). R-24-7068</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>


      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">26922</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caring for Aging Parents: The Essential Planning Guide</title>
      <link>
        https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/perspectives/caring-for-aging-parents-the-essential-planning-guide/</link>

      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Buckingham Strategic Partners]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 09:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/?p=26863</guid>

      <description><![CDATA[Caring for aging parents is a challenge many Americans are facing. What factors must you consider to ensure your loved ones are well taken care of mentally, physically, legally and financially? In an era marked by unprecedented longevity and shifting family dynamics, caring for aging parents is a challenge that many Americans are facing. Given...]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="font-weight: 400;">Caring for aging parents is a challenge many Americans are facing. What factors must you consider to ensure your loved ones are well taken care of mentally, physically, legally and financially?</p>
<p>In an era marked by unprecedented longevity and shifting family dynamics, caring for aging parents is a challenge that many Americans are facing. Given the large population of baby boomers, these numbers have increased significantly over the last several years and will continue to do so. Here are a few statistics illustrating the enormity of this growing situation:</p>
<ul>
<li>A recent American Association of Retired Persons (AARP) <a href="https://www.aarp.org/content/dam/aarp/ppi/2020/05/full-report-caregiving-in-the-united-states.doi.10.26419-2Fppi.00103.001.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">study</a> found as many as 48.1 million adults in the U.S. are serving as a caregiver to someone over age 50.</li>
<li>The Pew Research Center <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2018/11/08/adult-caregiving-often-seen-as-very-meaningful-by-those-who-do-it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">estimates</a> that approximately 15% of U.S. adults are caring for another adult without receiving compensation.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.caregiver.org/resource/caregiver-statistics-demographics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Research</a> from the Family Caregiver Alliance show that women are more likely to be providing this care as almost 75% of the caregivers in the U.S. are female.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Where to start</strong></h3>
<p>While these numbers may seem overwhelming, there are several steps you can take in advance to prepare in case you ever find yourself in the role of caregiver. To involve aging parents and ensure their wishes are clearly known, start the conversation about life planning earlier rather than later. If there are multiple children, schedule a family meeting with a clear agenda and objectives to confirm everyone is on the same page.</p>
<h3><strong>Understanding your aging parents’ needs</strong></h3>
<p>To begin, it is imperative to get a grasp on your parents’ overall physical and mental health. The conversation should address ongoing health issues, which medical providers they are using and any upcoming routine or one-off medical appointments. Make a list to document as much information as possible, adding in things like contact information for various providers and medications.</p>
<p>While this next step is often overlooked, it’s important to talk with your loved ones about what a typical day looks like for them. Learning about small tasks that might not be top of mind, such as getting mail or caring for a pet, can be valuable. This is also an opportunity to make observations and be sure that daily obligations can still be safely handled independently.</p>
<p>This can be a good time to talk through what is going well now, while also talking through their desires if the situation changes. Determine if there are other family members, friends or neighbors who could check in or help with day-to-day tasks as needed.</p>
<h3><strong>Financial and legal concerns</strong></h3>
<p>While there may not be a need for much ongoing support presently, it is important to think ahead so you can start addressing financial and legal concerns. If your loved ones work with a wealth advisor, this is a great time for you all to meet to review their assets and find out more about their overall financial situation. Start with a basic net worth analysis to determine what they own and if they have any debts. It is also important to help ensure their investment allocation still aligns with their current and upcoming spending needs. A financial advisor will be very helpful in providing guidance around the finances, specifically the investment allocation and long-term spending plan. It is imperative to have legal paperwork in place so that your parents’ wishes are documented. This includes a will, trust, financial power of attorney, medical power of attorney and a living will. A meeting with an estate planning attorney may be necessary to get these documents drafted or updated to reflect their wishes.</p>
<h3><strong>Care options</strong></h3>
<p>According to the Administration for Community Living (ACL) <a href="https://acl.gov/ltc/basic-needs/how-much-care-will-you-need" target="_blank" rel="noopener">website</a>, someone age 65 has a 70% probability of needing a form of long-term care services, and approximately 37% of people will need some type of care within a living facility. It is helpful to talk through what your parents’ wishes are if they need a higher level of care, while staying realistic about their options.</p>
<p>If a long-term care insurance policy is in place, review this in advance to determine what coverage is available. Typically, one cannot file a claim for this type of insurance coverage unless a person is unable to perform at least two activities of daily living (ADLs). However, once that criteria is met you may have options for in-home or out-of-home care, so it is important to understand what the plan covers and the policy’s parameters.</p>
<p>In-home caregiving possibilities may be performed by an unpaid family member or friend. Alternatively, you may hire a nurse or home health care aide to come into the residence. There are transportation services often available through local resources that can help provide a ride to appointments. It is also important to consider utilizing local resources to provide caregivers relief temporarily as needed. There are services such as adult day care centers or respite care facilities that are helpful to have lined up.</p>
<p>Many options are available for living outside the home. Independent, assisted living and memory care facilities can provide varying degrees of support. If you have the financial means, it might make sense for parents to move into a facility before selling the home to ensure they feel comfortable in their new surroundings.</p>
<p>In summary, this list is not exhaustive and only scratches the surface of everything that needs to be considered when supporting the mental, physical, legal and financial needs of aging parents. The best advice is to start planning early and get professionals involved to assist in the process. This includes consulting with your financial team along with your parents to help build the appropriate plan.</p>
<p><em>For informational and educational purposes only and should not be construed as specific investment, accounting, legal, or tax advice. Certain information is based on third party data and may become outdated or otherwise superseded without notice. Third party information is deemed to be reliable, but its accuracy and completeness cannot be guaranteed. Neither the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) nor any other federal or state agency have approved, determined the accuracy, or confirmed the adequacy of this article. R-24-7000</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>


      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">26863</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will the Dominance of U.S. Equity Performance Prevail?</title>
      <link>
        https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/perspectives/will-the-dominance-of-u-s-equity-performance-prevail/</link>

      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Kizer, CFA]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 13:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/?p=26885</guid>

      <description><![CDATA[Over the last five years, the U.S. equity market has had a dominant run relative to other equity investment strategies, like value investing or investing in international stocks. Will this relative dominance over 2023 and early 2024 of the U.S. equity market continue? In this episode of Buckingham Perspectives, Jared Kizer sheds light on a...]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the last five years, the U.S. equity market has had a dominant run relative to other equity investment strategies, like value investing or investing in international stocks. Will this relative dominance over 2023 and early 2024 of the U.S. equity market continue? In this episode of Buckingham Perspectives, Jared Kizer sheds light on a topic that received a lot of attention in the late 2010s and has started to rear its head again over the last year – the performance of the U.S. market relative to other asset classes.</p>
<p>If you have any questions please feel free to drop us a <a href="https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/contact/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">note</a>.</p>
<p><em><span dir="ltr" data-redactor-span="true">For informational and educational purposes only and should not be construed as specific investment, accounting, legal, or tax advice. Certain information is based on third party data and may become outdated or otherwise superseded without notice. Third party information is deemed to be reliable, but its accuracy and completeness cannot be guaranteed. The time frame chosen because of the dates of available data. The inception of the AIEQ ETF was 2017. Indices are not available for direct investment. Their performance does not reflect the expenses associated with the management of an actual portfolio nor do indices represent results of actual trading. Information from sources deemed reliable, but its accuracy cannot be guaranteed. Performance is historical and does not guarantee future results. All investments involve risk, including loss of principal. Neither the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) nor any other federal or state agency have approved, determined the accuracy, or confirmed the adequacy of this information.</span></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>


      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">26885</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Your Portfolio in a Presidential Election Year</title>
      <link>
        https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/perspectives/protecting-your-portfolio-in-a-presidential-election-year/</link>

      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Kizer, CFA]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 09:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/?p=26788</guid>

      <description><![CDATA[The 2024 presidential election is set to be a repeat of the Biden versus Trump contest of 2020. With both houses of Congress up for grabs, the stakes are high for either party, so it is understandable for the U.S. public to be nervous. Regardless of how the election plays out, political tensions will likely...]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 2024 presidential election is set to be a repeat of the Biden versus Trump contest of 2020. With both houses of Congress up for grabs, the stakes are high for either party, so it is understandable for the U.S. public to be nervous. Regardless of how the election plays out, political tensions will likely remain elevated throughout the next president’s term, adding to an already contentious global political climate. Against this backdrop, many investors are anxious about the possible impact on financial markets. Here’s what to keep in mind this election season.</p>
<h3>1. Geopolitical risks are already priced into markets</h3>
<p>For financial markets, geopolitical risk is not new. While there have certainly been periods when geopolitical risks were perceived to be more elevated, global markets are continuously pricing in these risks. For as long as markets have existed, stock prices have endured the risk of world wars, regional conflicts, revolutions and countless other geopolitical events. The historical record helps investors understand the risk in most traditional stock and bond allocations. However, it’s still possible that new events may reshape the historical record. When investors begin to worry that political risks are rising, we encourage them to think through this question: Setting aside the upcoming election, are you comfortable with the historical risks that your allocation has exhibited? If you aren’t sure, a good first step is speaking with your financial advisor to better understand the historical risk profile of your asset allocation. This can help you decide whether you are exposed to more risk than you’re comfortable taking.</p>
<h3>2<strong>. Election outcomes have little impact on stock markets, and the U.S. economy is better poised to withstand a global slowdown compared to other economies.</strong></h3>
<p>For the U.S. stock market, there is abundant evidence that the outcome of a presidential election has not systematically impacted the market one way or the other. What matters more are the federal policies pursued during the next administration’s term. However, just like with geopolitical risks, the markets price in how such policies could impact economic growth, inflation and other indicators.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-26803 size-full" src="https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/QI_ElectionGrowth1_2024_Blog.png" alt="bar chart with red and blue bars" width="2048" height="716" srcset="https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/QI_ElectionGrowth1_2024_Blog.png 2048w , https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/QI_ElectionGrowth1_2024_Blog-300x105.png 300w , https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/QI_ElectionGrowth1_2024_Blog-1024x358.png 1024w , https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/QI_ElectionGrowth1_2024_Blog-768x268.png 768w , https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/QI_ElectionGrowth1_2024_Blog-1536x537.png 1536w " sizes="(max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px" /></p>
<p><em>Source: Ken French Data Library for U.S. stock returns. Party information sourced from Office of the Historian and the Clerk of the House’s Office of Art and Archives.</em></p>
<p>Regardless of who’s in power, we believe the biggest long-term economic challenge for future administrations is the U.S. government’s growing size, both from a ﬁscal and regulatory perspective. With both parties divided on how to address the government’s growing debt, this will likely lead to slower global economic growth. Keep in mind, however, that the U.S. economy is much better positioned than virtually all other developed governments and should still be more resilient to ﬁscal risks compared to most economies.</p>
<h3>3.<strong> Investors benefit from favorable stock market pricing conditions.</strong></h3>
<p>While we covered how markets price in a range of political and economic risks, investors should also consider how a company’s stock price compares to the earnings it generates. Across most asset classes, the news is positive. Although U.S. stock market valuations are above their long-term averages, most other broad asset classes — including the U.S. bond market, global developed stock markets and emerging stock markets — are relatively close to historical valuation levels. Even for the U.S. stock market, while large-cap stocks are mostly above their historical valuation levels, smaller and more value-oriented companies have valuation levels closer to their historical averages. This leads to our final point: the importance of diversifying and avoiding the temptation to chase the investments with the highest returns.</p>
<h3>4.<strong> Diversification is your friend – especially during uncertain times. </strong></h3>
<p>While elections have the potential to reshape policies and legislation, it’s difficult to predict which sectors or industries could benefit. The most effective way to manage risk, whether geopolitical or otherwise, is broad diversification. In the current environment, U.S. large-cap stocks have made a comeback after struggling in 2022. Because of that recent strong performance, some investors may be tempted to lower their allocation to other types of stocks, like foreign stocks and smaller-company stocks. The outcome of the election will not influence whether these trends for stocks continue, and no one can successfully predict which stocks will outperform over the next year. That’s why we believe investors should maintain their allocations across global stock markets, as well as to high-quality bonds with relatively short maturities. They might also consider some allocation to inflation-protected Treasury bonds. Finally, depending on their risk profile, some investors may want to consider allocating to alternative investment strategies. While alternatives may not be appropriate for all investors due to their complexity, some strategies are less exposed to geopolitical risks than broad stock and bond markets.</p>
<p>If you still feel concerned about how the 2024 election could impact your portfolio, speak to your financial advisor about lowering your risk exposure and making sure your portfolio is well diversified. It doesn’t hurt to take a break from following the election coverage either.</p>
<p><em>For informational and educational purposes only and should not be construed as specific investment, accounting, legal, or tax advice. Certain information is based on third-party data and may become outdated or otherwise superseded without notice. Indices are not available for direct investment. Their performance does not reflect the expenses associated with the management of an actual portfolio nor do indices represent results of actual trading. Information from sources deemed reliable, but its accuracy cannot be guaranteed. Performance is historical and does not guarantee future results. All investments involve risk, including loss of principal. Neither the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) nor any other federal or state agency have approved, determined the accuracy, or confirmed the adequacy of this article. R-24-6959</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>


      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">26788</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Investors Should Stick With Global Stocks</title>
      <link>
        https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/perspectives/why-investors-should-stick-with-global-stocks/</link>

      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Grogan, CFA, CFP®]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 13:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/?p=26785</guid>

      <description><![CDATA[In 2023, U.S. stocks outperformed international, causing some investors to question the wisdom of global diversification. The challenge with a diversified portfolio is that you’ll always have some investments that are not doing as well as others. If you follow markets long enough, you’ll find that even large gaps in performance can close quickly. In...]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 2023, U.S. stocks outperformed international, causing some investors to question the wisdom of global diversification. The challenge with a diversified portfolio is that you’ll always have some investments that are not doing as well as others. If you follow markets long enough, you’ll find that even large gaps in performance can close quickly. In the early 2010s, after a period where U.S. stocks delivered negative returns over an entire decade, international stocks had positive, though modest, returns. Investors worried then about staying invested in U.S. stocks, until they eventually started outperforming. Today, our advice remains the same: stick with your long-term diversified portfolio.</p>
<p>If you have any questions please feel free to drop us a <a href="https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/contact/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">note</a>.</p>
<p><em><span dir="ltr" data-redactor-span="true">For informational and educational purposes only and should not be construed as specific investment, accounting, legal, or tax advice. Certain information is based on third party data and may become outdated or otherwise superseded without notice. Third party information is deemed to be reliable, but its accuracy and completeness cannot be guaranteed. The time frame chosen because of the dates of available data. The inception of the AIEQ ETF was 2017. Indices are not available for direct investment. Their performance does not reflect the expenses associated with the management of an actual portfolio nor do indices represent results of actual trading. Information from sources deemed reliable, but its accuracy cannot be guaranteed. Performance is historical and does not guarantee future results. All investments involve risk, including loss of principal. Neither the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) nor any other federal or state agency have approved, determined the accuracy, or confirmed the adequacy of this information.</span></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>


      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">26785</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Restricted Stock Units: A Guide to Your Organization’s Compensation
        Program</title>
      <link>
        https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/perspectives/demystifying-restricted-stock-units-a-guide-to-your-organizations-compensation-program/</link>

      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Buckingham Strategic Partners]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 01:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/?p=26742</guid>

      <description><![CDATA[Congratulations! As part of your organization’s compensation program, you’ve been given restricted stock units (RSUs). You’re probably thrilled by the potential extra income, but amid the excitement, it’s important to understand what RSUs entail and how to maximize their benefit. RSU basics RSUs are shares of company stock given to an employee. This incentive is...]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-22482" style="padding: 15px 15px;" src="https://150228245.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/restricted-stocks-1600-900.png" alt="Demystifying Restricted Stock Units: A Guide to Your Organization’s Compensation Program" width="500px" /></p>
<p>Congratulations! As part of your organization’s compensation program, you’ve been given restricted stock units (RSUs). You’re probably thrilled by the potential extra income, but amid the excitement, it’s important to understand what RSUs entail and how to maximize their benefit. </p>
</div>
<p><strong>RSU basics</strong><br />
	RSUs are shares of company stock given to an employee. This incentive is commonly used to retain top talent by providing associates with an economic interest in the organization. They are typically given in tranches and vest over several years, meaning you cannot sell the stock or access the funds right away. The amount given usually relates to how well the company did that year and can be tied to an employee’s goals or team performance. Since RSUs are complex and each company’s approach is different, it’s important to review the documents provided when granted RSUs to really understand your specific stock unit plan.</p>
<p><strong>All that glitters is not gold</strong><br />
	While RSUs may be a profitable form of equity compensation, there are some cons you must consider. When receiving a large volume of a single stock, understanding the amount of risk you can and want to take with your portfolio is vital. This is different for everyone, but individual stocks are inherently riskier than diversified portfolios. When the stock is from your employer, this risk is increased, and if the company isn’t doing well, your source of regular income could also be in danger. A financial advisor can help you determine how much risk is appropriate for you to achieve your goals.</p>
<p><strong>Don’t forget about taxes</strong><br />
	Without proper planning, RSUs can result in a large tax bill. Typically, when RSUs vest, the full amount of the shares is taxable as ordinary income on the date they vest. This is true even if you don’t sell your shares, so it’s important to have a plan to pay the applicable federal and state taxes. Although most companies default to automatically selling a portion of the shares for tax withholding upon vesting (for example, selling 22% of your shares automatically and going to federal taxes), this is not always the case.</p>
<p>Ensuring you either have withholding from your shares or are making adequate estimated payments will help you avoid penalties and decrease your tax bill when you file. It’s also advisable to keep an eye on the share price as your vesting date approaches, as the potential income can be a lot higher than you may have anticipated if the share price has increased.</p>
<p>RSU shares vesting can also catapult you into a higher tax bracket, meaning you may be paying more in taxes than you otherwise would be. One of the best ways to minimize this impact is to maximize your deductions within the year the shares vest. Depending on your specific goals, this can potentially mean funding a 529 college savings plan or a health savings account (HSA). If you’re itemizing deductions, you may want to push as many tax deductions as possible into the present year &#8211; such as prepaying property taxes for the following year &#8211; depending on your total state tax. If giving back to charity or your church is important to you, it could be a good year to give a larger amount or consider funding a charitable donor advised fund (DAF) to continue gifting in future years.</p>
<p><strong>Once your vesting requirements are met</strong><br />
	Make sure you are incorporating your vested RSUs in your retirement plan. It can be tempting to count on your unvested shares in your financial future but try to limit that as much as possible. When the shares do vest, it will just make the picture even brighter. RSU sums can add up quickly and make a substantial impact on your goals.</p>
<p>When RSUs vest, they’re usually put into a brokerage account in individual name. Depending on the amount within the account and state laws, this could cause your estate to go through probate if something were to happen to you. Talk with your estate planning attorney to explore if it makes sense to journal funds from the individual account to a joint or trust account when they vest to avoid this possible complication.</p>
<p><strong>Maximize your RSUs</strong><br />
	Receiving stock compensation in the form of RSUs can be hugely beneficial. But knowing the right way to leverage and ensure you are not missing out on potential value – or paying more in taxes than you could be – makes it all the better.</p>
<p><em>Informational and educational purposes only and should not be construed as specific investment, accounting, legal, or tax advice. Certain information is based on third party data and may become outdated or otherwise superseded without notice. Third party data is deemed to be reliable, but its accuracy and completeness cannot be guaranteed. Neither the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) nor any other federal or state agency have approved, determined the accuracy, or confirmed the adequacy of this article. R-24-6876</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>


      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">26742</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do Election Years Affect Investing Behavior?</title>
      <link>
        https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/perspectives/how-do-election-years-affect-investing-behavior/</link>

      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Grogan, CFA, CFP®]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 15:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/?p=26732</guid>

      <description><![CDATA[In this episode of Buckingham Perspectives, Chief Investment Officer Kevin Grogan provides insight into the impact of presidential administrations on investor behavior. During presidential election years, a question that often comes up is how do markets fare when a Democrat versus a Republican controls the White House? The historical data show there isn’t a statistically...]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this episode of Buckingham Perspectives, Chief Investment Officer Kevin Grogan provides insight into the impact of presidential administrations on investor behavior. During presidential election years, a question that often comes up is how do markets fare when a Democrat versus a Republican controls the White House? The historical data show there isn’t a statistically significant difference in market performance, regardless of who’s in power. However, an individual investor’s optimism about the party in power may impact their investment performance – and we’d encourage you to stick to your long-term plan no matter what happens this election year.</p>
<p>If you have any questions please feel free to drop us a <a href="https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/contact/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">note</a>.</p>
<p><em><span dir="ltr" data-redactor-span="true">For informational and educational purposes only and should not be construed as specific investment, accounting, legal, or tax advice. Certain information is based on third party data and may become outdated or otherwise superseded without notice. Third party information is deemed to be reliable, but its accuracy and completeness cannot be guaranteed. The time frame chosen because of the dates of available data. The inception of the AIEQ ETF was 2017. Indices are not available for direct investment. Their performance does not reflect the expenses associated with the management of an actual portfolio nor do indices represent results of actual trading. Information from sources deemed reliable, but its accuracy cannot be guaranteed. Performance is historical and does not guarantee future results. All investments involve risk, including loss of principal. Neither the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) nor any other federal or state agency have approved, determined the accuracy, or confirmed the adequacy of this information.</span></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>


      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">26732</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Your Advisor Can Build a Plan Based on Your Values</title>
      <link>
        https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/perspectives/how-your-advisor-can-build-a-plan-based-on-your-values/</link>

      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Buckingham Strategic Partners]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://buckinghamstrategicpartners.com/?p=26305</guid>

      <description><![CDATA[Your financial plan should have the same philosophy as the rest of your life. Your values—or what matters most to you—drive every decision you make in life, including the hobbies or activities you participate in, the causes you support and the people you spend your time with. Your financial plan should be driven by the...]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Your financial plan should have the same philosophy as the rest of your life. Your values—or what matters most to you—drive every decision you make in life, including the hobbies or activities you participate in, the causes you support and the people you spend your time with. Your financial plan should be driven by the same factors. An advisor should never recommend a product, strategy or service before knowing what you want to accomplish. So, let’s look at the ways an advisor can build a financial plan based on your values, throughout different areas of financial planning.</p>
<h3><strong>1. Defining your values and goals.</strong></h3>
<p>When developing a financial plan, you should avoid making decisions solely based on instinct, gut feeling or simply rolling the dice. An advisor helps discover what goals are most important to you and then designs your financial plan based on evidence. Maybe you don’t know what you hope to achieve with your assets quite yet, but you value simplicity. An independent wealth advisor can simplify your plan by recommending only what you need to grow and protect your assets—not a product, strategy or service you don’t need. Or you may seek an advisor to manage your plan so you can focus on activities and people you value most. When making investing decisions, it’s easy to get caught up in topics that elicit exciting headlines and rumors about quick ways to get rich. Your advisor can also help you filter what’s important and what’s not about your financial plan.</p>
<h3><strong>2. Guiding your investing strategy to align with your values and goals.</strong></h3>
<p><strong>Focusing on goals:</strong> Your advisor helps your <a href="https://investing.buckinghamstrategicwealth.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">investments work toward what’s most important to you</a> by finding the right asset allocation, risk tolerance and asset classes so you can accomplish your goals. Remember, your benchmark isn’t the S&amp;P 500, the Dow Jones or the Nasdaq. Your benchmark is your goals.</p>
<p><strong>Minimizing investing costs:</strong> It’s hard to think of any situation where you’d want to pay more than you need to. This is especially true when it comes to investments. <a href="https://www.sec.gov/investor/alerts/ib_fees_expenses.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Data shows</a> that fees, expenses and taxes can be the biggest drag on investment returns. An advisor will look for the most cost-efficient funds so that you keep more of what you make.</p>
<p><strong>Making decisions based on evidence:</strong> It’s normal to get excited about a hot new stock or product that everyone is talking about. But the investing universe is full of fads that die just as quickly as they come. That’s why it’s important to build your portfolio with investments that have a history of consistent returns.</p>
<p><strong>Allocating to causes you’re passionate about:</strong> There are funds that support social causes, religious values or other lifestyle values, including environmental, social and governance (ESG) funds. If ESG is something that interests you, it’s important to talk with a professional about the added risks that come with screening out specific companies or industries. With fewer companies to invest in, you’re reducing your options for diversification. An advisor can help you make the best choice for your investment portfolio while maximizing the impact you’re making.</p>
<h3><strong>3. Suggesting strategies to make the biggest impact with your money.</strong></h3>
<p>A trustworthy financial advisor will not only ensure you give to charities or family members in the most tax-efficient way, but they’ll also make sure your gifting strategy is in line with your overall goals and values. This could mean finding the best way to contribute to <a href="https://buckinghamstrategicwealth.com/resources/charitable-giving/4-charitable-giving-strategies-to-maximize-your-impact" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a donor advised fund</a>, or determining whether you should give cash, or funds, from your IRA by making qualified charitable deductions (if you’re over age 70.5). Or maybe you want to <a href="https://buckinghamstrategicwealth.com/resources/estate-trust/strategies-for-effective-gifting-to-family-members" target="_blank" rel="noopener">give money to loved ones</a> but aren’t sure about the rules around gifting.</p>
<p>An advisor will help you navigate rules for transferring different types of assets to individuals or entities. If you want to distribute assets during your lifetime, an advisor (along with your accountant) can help you find the best way to distribute them. For example, if you hold stocks with large gains, it might make sense to transfer these to a charity or tax-exempt organization because they’ll pay no taxes on the gains. If you have income-producing assets, your advisor can help you transfer these to loved ones who are in low-income brackets.</p>
<h3><strong>4. Ensuring your values are built into your estate planning.</strong></h3>
<p>Estate planning is how you decide who will receive your assets, what assets will be passed on, and how. Regardless of their values, most people want to have a say in this. An advisor can work with your estate planning attorney to make sure your assets are in line with your estate plan (or help you find an attorney).</p>
<p>When it comes to selecting beneficiaries and factoring in your charitable wishes, your advisor can work with your estate planning attorney to make sure your assets are set up according to your estate plan. This might mean that you plan to give taxable assets to children so they can take advantage of the step-up in basis, which reduces their taxes on the inheritance. And you could give pre-tax assets directly to charities, so your heirs don’t pay taxes on the distributions.</p>
<h3><strong>5. Prioritizing your values-based goals in retirement.</strong></h3>
<p>Maybe you value simply having enough money for retirement. An advisor can help you contribute to the right accounts, determine whether you should take a pension buyout, decide when to draw Social Security, and figure out which accounts to draw from in retirement. An advisor can also help you figure out how long you need to work or if you have enough savings to cut back to part time. If you own a business, an advisor can strategize your succession plan. <a href="https://www.fidelity.com/viewpoints/retirement/spending-in-retirement" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Data shows</a> that you spend a certain amount of your savings on leisure activities until a certain age, at which point health care becomes your main expense. Your advisor can develop a spending plan so you can prioritize doing what you love while maintaining peace of mind that you’ll have enough ready for future medical bills.</p>
<p>Advisors are resourceful, and their true employer is the client. Your advisor works for you. So, take advantage of the resources that advisors have access to, and align your financial plan with whatever is most valuable to you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>


      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">26305</post-id>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
